{"FIN_SIT_W54": {"MC_options": ["Live comfortably", "Meet your basic expenses with a little left over for extras", "Just meet your basic expenses", "\"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses\"", "Refused"], "question_text": "How would you describe your household's financial situation?", "Asian": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 6.0, "Just meet your basic expenses": 27.0, "Live comfortably": 82.0, "Meet your basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 92.0}, "Black": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 83.0, "Just meet your basic expenses": 221.0, "Live comfortably": 111.0, "Meet your basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 288.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Hispanic": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 17.0, "Just meet your basic expenses": 106.0, "Live comfortably": 88.0, "Meet your basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 155.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Mixed Race": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 13.0, "Just meet your basic expenses": 29.0, "Live comfortably": 48.0, "Meet your basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 91.0}, "Other": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 3.0, "Just meet your basic expenses": 10.0, "Live comfortably": 15.0, "Meet your basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 18.0}, "Refused": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 6.0, "Just meet your basic expenses": 16.0, "Live comfortably": 36.0, "Meet your basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 40.0, "Refused": 2.0}, "White": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 243.0, "Just meet your basic expenses": 860.0, "Live comfortably": 2090.0, "Meet your basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 2070.0, "Refused": 10.0}}, "FIN_SITMOST_W54": {"MC_options": ["Live comfortably", "Meet their basic expenses with a little left over for extras", "Just meet their basic expenses", "\"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses\"", "Refused"], "question_text": "How would you describe the financial situation of most Americans?", "Asian": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 18.0, "Just meet their basic expenses": 98.0, "Live comfortably": 10.0, "Meet their basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 81.0}, "Black": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 110.0, "Just meet their basic expenses": 344.0, "Live comfortably": 27.0, "Meet their basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 220.0, "Refused": 3.0}, "Hispanic": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 42.0, "Just meet their basic expenses": 180.0, "Live comfortably": 18.0, "Meet their basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 125.0, "Refused": 2.0}, "Mixed Race": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 17.0, "Just meet their basic expenses": 93.0, "Live comfortably": 7.0, "Meet their basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 63.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Other": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 7.0, "Just meet their basic expenses": 20.0, "Live comfortably": 2.0, "Meet their basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 17.0}, "Refused": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 8.0, "Just meet their basic expenses": 38.0, "Live comfortably": 8.0, "Meet their basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 45.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "White": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 392.0, "Just meet their basic expenses": 2524.0, "Live comfortably": 217.0, "Meet their basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 2106.0, "Refused": 34.0}}, "FIN_SITCOMM_W54": {"MC_options": ["Live comfortably", "Meet their basic expenses with a little left over for extras", "Just meet their basic expenses", "\"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses\"", "Refused"], "question_text": "How would you describe the financial situation of most people in the area where you live?", "Asian": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 6.0, "Just meet their basic expenses": 39.0, "Live comfortably": 71.0, "Meet their basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 91.0}, "Black": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 67.0, "Just meet their basic expenses": 240.0, "Live comfortably": 95.0, "Meet their basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 301.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Hispanic": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 22.0, "Just meet their basic expenses": 128.0, "Live comfortably": 64.0, "Meet their basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 151.0, "Refused": 2.0}, "Mixed Race": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 13.0, "Just meet their basic expenses": 44.0, "Live comfortably": 32.0, "Meet their basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 92.0}, "Other": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 4.0, "Just meet their basic expenses": 16.0, "Live comfortably": 9.0, "Meet their basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 17.0}, "Refused": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 6.0, "Just meet their basic expenses": 19.0, "Live comfortably": 27.0, "Meet their basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 45.0, "Refused": 3.0}, "White": {"Don't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 272.0, "Just meet their basic expenses": 1162.0, "Live comfortably": 1441.0, "Meet their basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 2381.0, "Refused": 17.0}}, "FIN_SITGROWUP_W54": {"MC_options": ["Lived comfortably", "Met basic expenses with a little left over for extras", "Just met basic expenses", "\"Didn't even have enough to meet basic expenses\"", "Refused"], "question_text": "Now thinking about when you were growing up, how would you describe your family's financial situation for most of the time when you were growing up?", "Asian": {"Didn't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 24.0, "Just met basic expenses": 60.0, "Lived comfortably": 41.0, "Met basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 81.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Black": {"Didn't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 128.0, "Just met basic expenses": 212.0, "Lived comfortably": 147.0, "Met basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 215.0, "Refused": 2.0}, "Hispanic": {"Didn't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 60.0, "Just met basic expenses": 124.0, "Lived comfortably": 71.0, "Met basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 112.0}, "Mixed Race": {"Didn't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 27.0, "Just met basic expenses": 57.0, "Lived comfortably": 35.0, "Met basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 62.0}, "Other": {"Didn't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 6.0, "Just met basic expenses": 17.0, "Lived comfortably": 9.0, "Met basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 14.0}, "Refused": {"Didn't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 14.0, "Just met basic expenses": 22.0, "Lived comfortably": 26.0, "Met basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 37.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "White": {"Didn't even have enough to meet basic expenses": 491.0, "Just met basic expenses": 1372.0, "Lived comfortably": 1328.0, "Met basic expenses with a little left over for extras": 2076.0, "Refused": 6.0}}, "GOVPRIORITYa_W54": {"MC_options": ["A top priority", "Important", "but lower priority", "Not too important", "Should not be done", "Refused"], "question_text": "How much of a priority should the following be for the federal government to address: Making health care more affordable", "Asian": {"A top priority": 160.0, "Important, but lower priority": 43.0, "Not too important": 3.0, "Should not be done": 1.0}, "Black": {"A top priority": 614.0, "Important, but lower priority": 75.0, "Not too important": 8.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Should not be done": 4.0}, "Hispanic": {"A top priority": 287.0, "Important, but lower priority": 60.0, "Not too important": 13.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Should not be done": 5.0}, "Mixed Race": {"A top priority": 125.0, "Important, but lower priority": 43.0, "Not too important": 7.0, "Should not be done": 6.0}, "Other": {"A top priority": 37.0, "Important, but lower priority": 6.0, "Not too important": 1.0, "Should not be done": 2.0}, "Refused": {"A top priority": 60.0, "Important, but lower priority": 25.0, "Not too important": 9.0, "Should not be done": 6.0}, "White": {"A top priority": 3677.0, "Important, but lower priority": 1254.0, "Not too important": 214.0, "Refused": 16.0, "Should not be done": 112.0}}, "GOVPRIORITYb_W54": {"MC_options": ["A top priority", "Important", "but lower priority", "Not too important", "Should not be done", "Refused"], "question_text": "How much of a priority should the following be for the federal government to address: Reducing illegal immigration", "Asian": {"A top priority": 54.0, "Important, but lower priority": 88.0, "Not too important": 60.0, "Should not be done": 5.0}, "Black": {"A top priority": 172.0, "Important, but lower priority": 323.0, "Not too important": 178.0, "Refused": 4.0, "Should not be done": 27.0}, "Hispanic": {"A top priority": 69.0, "Important, but lower priority": 158.0, "Not too important": 114.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Should not be done": 25.0}, "Mixed Race": {"A top priority": 57.0, "Important, but lower priority": 66.0, "Not too important": 53.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Should not be done": 4.0}, "Other": {"A top priority": 18.0, "Important, but lower priority": 18.0, "Not too important": 7.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Should not be done": 2.0}, "Refused": {"A top priority": 44.0, "Important, but lower priority": 32.0, "Not too important": 17.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Should not be done": 6.0}, "White": {"A top priority": 2103.0, "Important, but lower priority": 1710.0, "Not too important": 1249.0, "Refused": 15.0, "Should not be done": 196.0}}, "GOVPRIORITYc_W54": {"MC_options": ["A top priority", "Important", "but lower priority", "Not too important", "Should not be done", "Refused"], "question_text": "How much of a priority should the following be for the federal government to address: Reducing economic inequality", "Asian": {"A top priority": 107.0, "Important, but lower priority": 80.0, "Not too important": 15.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Should not be done": 4.0}, "Black": {"A top priority": 485.0, "Important, but lower priority": 169.0, "Not too important": 33.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Should not be done": 15.0}, "Hispanic": {"A top priority": 197.0, "Important, but lower priority": 126.0, "Not too important": 33.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Should not be done": 10.0}, "Mixed Race": {"A top priority": 87.0, "Important, but lower priority": 57.0, "Not too important": 27.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Should not be done": 8.0}, "Other": {"A top priority": 21.0, "Important, but lower priority": 20.0, "Not too important": 3.0, "Should not be done": 2.0}, "Refused": {"A top priority": 36.0, "Important, but lower priority": 39.0, "Not too important": 10.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Should not be done": 14.0}, "White": {"A top priority": 2032.0, "Important, but lower priority": 1992.0, "Not too important": 823.0, "Refused": 37.0, "Should not be done": 389.0}}, "GOVPRIORITYd_W54": {"MC_options": ["A top priority", "Important", "but lower priority", "Not too important", "Should not be done", "Refused"], "question_text": "How much of a priority should the following be for the federal government to address: Addressing climate change", "Asian": {"A top priority": 128.0, "Important, but lower priority": 62.0, "Not too important": 13.0, "Should not be done": 4.0}, "Black": {"A top priority": 399.0, "Important, but lower priority": 211.0, "Not too important": 72.0, "Refused": 5.0, "Should not be done": 17.0}, "Hispanic": {"A top priority": 228.0, "Important, but lower priority": 94.0, "Not too important": 30.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Should not be done": 12.0}, "Mixed Race": {"A top priority": 94.0, "Important, but lower priority": 48.0, "Not too important": 24.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Should not be done": 13.0}, "Other": {"A top priority": 24.0, "Important, but lower priority": 10.0, "Not too important": 10.0, "Should not be done": 2.0}, "Refused": {"A top priority": 45.0, "Important, but lower priority": 25.0, "Not too important": 17.0, "Should not be done": 13.0}, "White": {"A top priority": 2611.0, "Important, but lower priority": 1327.0, "Not too important": 859.0, "Refused": 12.0, "Should not be done": 464.0}}, "GOVPRIORITYe_W54": {"MC_options": ["A top priority", "Important", "but lower priority", "Not too important", "Should not be done", "Refused"], "question_text": "How much of a priority should the following be for the federal government to address: Dealing with terrorism", "Asian": {"A top priority": 112.0, "Important, but lower priority": 71.0, "Not too important": 22.0, "Should not be done": 2.0}, "Black": {"A top priority": 513.0, "Important, but lower priority": 151.0, "Not too important": 28.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Should not be done": 9.0}, "Hispanic": {"A top priority": 218.0, "Important, but lower priority": 114.0, "Not too important": 33.0, "Refused": 2.0}, "Mixed Race": {"A top priority": 111.0, "Important, but lower priority": 57.0, "Not too important": 11.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Should not be done": 1.0}, "Other": {"A top priority": 31.0, "Important, but lower priority": 10.0, "Not too important": 3.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Should not be done": 1.0}, "Refused": {"A top priority": 69.0, "Important, but lower priority": 24.0, "Not too important": 6.0, "Should not be done": 1.0}, "White": {"A top priority": 3339.0, "Important, but lower priority": 1573.0, "Not too important": 327.0, "Refused": 15.0, "Should not be done": 19.0}}, "GOVPRIORITYf_W54": {"MC_options": ["A top priority", "Important", "but lower priority", "Not too important", "Should not be done", "Refused"], "question_text": "How much of a priority should the following be for the federal government to address: Reducing gun violence", "Asian": {"A top priority": 157.0, "Important, but lower priority": 42.0, "Not too important": 6.0, "Should not be done": 2.0}, "Black": {"A top priority": 583.0, "Important, but lower priority": 94.0, "Not too important": 21.0, "Refused": 5.0, "Should not be done": 1.0}, "Hispanic": {"A top priority": 260.0, "Important, but lower priority": 70.0, "Not too important": 27.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Should not be done": 9.0}, "Mixed Race": {"A top priority": 108.0, "Important, but lower priority": 45.0, "Not too important": 19.0, "Should not be done": 9.0}, "Other": {"A top priority": 30.0, "Important, but lower priority": 10.0, "Not too important": 4.0, "Should not be done": 2.0}, "Refused": {"A top priority": 57.0, "Important, but lower priority": 24.0, "Not too important": 10.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Should not be done": 7.0}, "White": {"A top priority": 2956.0, "Important, but lower priority": 1616.0, "Not too important": 505.0, "Refused": 20.0, "Should not be done": 176.0}}, "GOVRESP_a_W54": {"MC_options": ["Yes", "a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans", "No", "not the responsibility of the federal government to provide", "Refused"], "question_text": "Do you think an adequate standard of living is something the federal government has a responsibility to provide for all Americans?", "Asian": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 56.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 151.0}, "Black": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 147.0, "Refused": 6.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 551.0}, "Hispanic": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 116.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 249.0}, "Mixed Race": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 77.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 104.0}, "Other": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 21.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 25.0}, "Refused": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 52.0, "Refused": 4.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 44.0}, "White": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 2636.0, "Refused": 39.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 2598.0}}, "GOVRESP_b_W54": {"MC_options": ["Yes", "a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans", "No", "not the responsibility of the federal government to provide", "Refused"], "question_text": "Do you think adequate housing is something the federal government has a responsibility to provide for all Americans?", "Asian": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 74.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 132.0}, "Black": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 157.0, "Refused": 4.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 543.0}, "Hispanic": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 126.0, "Refused": 5.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 236.0}, "Mixed Race": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 79.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 101.0}, "Other": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 18.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 28.0}, "Refused": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 53.0, "Refused": 4.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 43.0}, "White": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 3027.0, "Refused": 40.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 2206.0}}, "GOVRESP_c_W54": {"MC_options": ["Yes", "a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans", "No", "not the responsibility of the federal government to provide", "Refused"], "question_text": "Do you think high quality K-12 education is something the federal government has a responsibility to provide for all Americans?", "Asian": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 29.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 178.0}, "Black": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 58.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 644.0}, "Hispanic": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 45.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 320.0}, "Mixed Race": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 27.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 154.0}, "Other": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 10.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 36.0}, "Refused": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 26.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 73.0}, "White": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 1152.0, "Refused": 27.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 4094.0}}, "GOVRESP_d_W54": {"MC_options": ["Yes", "a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans", "No", "not the responsibility of the federal government to provide", "Refused"], "question_text": "Do you think a college education is something the federal government has a responsibility to provide for all Americans?", "Asian": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 102.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 104.0}, "Black": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 280.0, "Refused": 7.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 417.0}, "Hispanic": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 150.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 215.0}, "Mixed Race": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 115.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 64.0}, "Other": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 28.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 18.0}, "Refused": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 61.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 37.0}, "White": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 3879.0, "Refused": 32.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 1362.0}}, "GOVRESP_e_W54": {"MC_options": ["Yes", "a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans", "No", "not the responsibility of the federal government to provide", "Refused"], "question_text": "Do you think adequate income in retirement is something the federal government has a responsibility to provide for all Americans?", "Asian": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 78.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 129.0}, "Black": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 171.0, "Refused": 6.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 527.0}, "Hispanic": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 91.0, "Refused": 6.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 270.0}, "Mixed Race": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 67.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 114.0}, "Other": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 18.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 28.0}, "Refused": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 45.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 52.0}, "White": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 2540.0, "Refused": 33.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 2700.0}}, "GOVRESP_h_W54": {"MC_options": ["Yes", "a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans", "No", "not the responsibility of the federal government to provide", "Refused"], "question_text": "Do you think access to high-speed internet is something the federal government has a responsibility to provide for all Americans?", "Asian": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 115.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 91.0}, "Black": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 457.0, "Refused": 4.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 243.0}, "Hispanic": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 253.0, "Refused": 5.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 109.0}, "Mixed Race": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 125.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 54.0}, "Other": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 32.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 13.0}, "Refused": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 74.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 24.0}, "White": {"No, not the responsibility of the federal government to provide": 3852.0, "Refused": 33.0, "Yes, a responsibility of the federal government to provide for all Americans": 1388.0}}, "ECON1_W54": {"MC_options": ["Excellent", "Good", "Only fair", "Poor", "Refused"], "question_text": "Thinking about the nation's economy, how would you rate economic conditions in this country today?", "Asian": {"Excellent": 16.0, "Good": 104.0, "Only fair": 71.0, "Poor": 15.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Black": {"Excellent": 23.0, "Good": 212.0, "Only fair": 356.0, "Poor": 113.0}, "Hispanic": {"Excellent": 24.0, "Good": 138.0, "Only fair": 167.0, "Poor": 35.0, "Refused": 3.0}, "Mixed Race": {"Excellent": 16.0, "Good": 76.0, "Only fair": 77.0, "Poor": 12.0}, "Other": {"Excellent": 6.0, "Good": 19.0, "Only fair": 10.0, "Poor": 11.0}, "Refused": {"Excellent": 12.0, "Good": 47.0, "Only fair": 32.0, "Poor": 8.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "White": {"Excellent": 641.0, "Good": 2616.0, "Only fair": 1700.0, "Poor": 307.0, "Refused": 9.0}}, "ECON1B_W54": {"MC_options": ["Better", "Worse", "About the same as now", "Refused"], "question_text": "A year from now, do you expect that economic conditions in the country as a whole will be", "Asian": {"About the same as now": 84.0, "Better": 38.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Worse": 82.0}, "Black": {"About the same as now": 349.0, "Better": 89.0, "Worse": 266.0}, "Hispanic": {"About the same as now": 148.0, "Better": 74.0, "Worse": 145.0}, "Mixed Race": {"About the same as now": 77.0, "Better": 37.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Worse": 66.0}, "Other": {"About the same as now": 17.0, "Better": 13.0, "Worse": 16.0}, "Refused": {"About the same as now": 47.0, "Better": 26.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Worse": 25.0}, "White": {"About the same as now": 2481.0, "Better": 977.0, "Refused": 22.0, "Worse": 1793.0}}, "ECON3_a_W54": {"MC_options": ["A great deal", "A fair amount", "Not too much", "Not at all", "Refused"], "question_text": "How much, if at all, do you think the availability of jobs is contributing to your opinion about how the economy is doing?", "Asian": {"A fair amount": 84.0, "A great deal": 95.0, "Not at all": 4.0, "Not too much": 21.0, "Refused": 3.0}, "Black": {"A fair amount": 235.0, "A great deal": 343.0, "Not at all": 29.0, "Not too much": 95.0, "Refused": 2.0}, "Hispanic": {"A fair amount": 150.0, "A great deal": 161.0, "Not at all": 6.0, "Not too much": 46.0, "Refused": 4.0}, "Mixed Race": {"A fair amount": 68.0, "A great deal": 80.0, "Not at all": 2.0, "Not too much": 30.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Other": {"A fair amount": 20.0, "A great deal": 21.0, "Not at all": 2.0, "Not too much": 3.0}, "Refused": {"A fair amount": 43.0, "A great deal": 40.0, "Not at all": 1.0, "Not too much": 15.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "White": {"A fair amount": 2158.0, "A great deal": 2396.0, "Not at all": 108.0, "Not too much": 581.0, "Refused": 30.0}}, "ECON3_b_W54": {"MC_options": ["A great deal", "A fair amount", "Not too much", "Not at all", "Refused"], "question_text": "How much, if at all, do you think how the stock market is doing is contributing to your opinion about how the economy is doing?", "Asian": {"A fair amount": 95.0, "A great deal": 68.0, "Not at all": 1.0, "Not too much": 40.0, "Refused": 3.0}, "Black": {"A fair amount": 270.0, "A great deal": 168.0, "Not at all": 90.0, "Not too much": 169.0, "Refused": 7.0}, "Hispanic": {"A fair amount": 158.0, "A great deal": 90.0, "Not at all": 21.0, "Not too much": 90.0, "Refused": 8.0}, "Mixed Race": {"A fair amount": 89.0, "A great deal": 36.0, "Not at all": 20.0, "Not too much": 35.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Other": {"A fair amount": 23.0, "A great deal": 10.0, "Not at all": 6.0, "Not too much": 7.0}, "Refused": {"A fair amount": 45.0, "A great deal": 21.0, "Not at all": 10.0, "Not too much": 23.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "White": {"A fair amount": 2512.0, "A great deal": 1299.0, "Not at all": 290.0, "Not too much": 1124.0, "Refused": 48.0}}, "ECON3_h_W54": {"MC_options": ["A great deal", "A fair amount", "Not too much", "Not at all", "Refused"], "question_text": "How much, if at all, do you think wages and incomes are contributing to your opinion about how the economy is doing?", "Asian": {"A fair amount": 96.0, "A great deal": 94.0, "Not at all": 2.0, "Not too much": 14.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Black": {"A fair amount": 178.0, "A great deal": 413.0, "Not at all": 33.0, "Not too much": 76.0, "Refused": 4.0}, "Hispanic": {"A fair amount": 106.0, "A great deal": 194.0, "Not at all": 12.0, "Not too much": 51.0, "Refused": 4.0}, "Mixed Race": {"A fair amount": 53.0, "A great deal": 106.0, "Not at all": 6.0, "Not too much": 16.0}, "Other": {"A fair amount": 15.0, "A great deal": 26.0, "Not at all": 1.0, "Not too much": 4.0}, "Refused": {"A fair amount": 41.0, "A great deal": 46.0, "Not at all": 5.0, "Not too much": 6.0, "Refused": 2.0}, "White": {"A fair amount": 2289.0, "A great deal": 2476.0, "Not at all": 69.0, "Not too much": 406.0, "Refused": 33.0}}, "ECON3_i_W54": {"MC_options": ["A great deal", "A fair amount", "Not too much", "Not at all", "Refused"], "question_text": "How much, if at all, do you think the country's tax system is contributing to your opinion about how the economy is doing?", "Asian": {"A fair amount": 86.0, "A great deal": 78.0, "Not at all": 8.0, "Not too much": 35.0}, "Black": {"A fair amount": 247.0, "A great deal": 308.0, "Not at all": 39.0, "Not too much": 105.0, "Refused": 5.0}, "Hispanic": {"A fair amount": 120.0, "A great deal": 159.0, "Not at all": 13.0, "Not too much": 69.0, "Refused": 6.0}, "Mixed Race": {"A fair amount": 74.0, "A great deal": 80.0, "Not at all": 6.0, "Not too much": 21.0}, "Other": {"A fair amount": 23.0, "A great deal": 13.0, "Not at all": 1.0, "Not too much": 9.0}, "Refused": {"A fair amount": 34.0, "A great deal": 36.0, "Not at all": 9.0, "Not too much": 19.0, "Refused": 2.0}, "White": {"A fair amount": 2161.0, "A great deal": 1806.0, "Not at all": 246.0, "Not too much": 1010.0, "Refused": 50.0}}, "ECON4_a_W54": {"MC_options": ["A great deal", "A fair amount", "Not too much", "Not at all", "Refused"], "question_text": "Thinking about your own household's financial situation, how much, if at all, does the availability of jobs in your area affect your household's financial situation?", "Asian": {"A fair amount": 65.0, "A great deal": 72.0, "Not at all": 24.0, "Not too much": 45.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Black": {"A fair amount": 190.0, "A great deal": 306.0, "Not at all": 76.0, "Not too much": 130.0, "Refused": 2.0}, "Hispanic": {"A fair amount": 117.0, "A great deal": 124.0, "Not at all": 39.0, "Not too much": 82.0, "Refused": 5.0}, "Mixed Race": {"A fair amount": 61.0, "A great deal": 50.0, "Not at all": 28.0, "Not too much": 42.0}, "Other": {"A fair amount": 10.0, "A great deal": 17.0, "Not at all": 9.0, "Not too much": 9.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Refused": {"A fair amount": 33.0, "A great deal": 22.0, "Not at all": 17.0, "Not too much": 26.0, "Refused": 2.0}, "White": {"A fair amount": 1568.0, "A great deal": 1152.0, "Not at all": 958.0, "Not too much": 1574.0, "Refused": 21.0}}, "ECON4_b_W54": {"MC_options": ["A great deal", "A fair amount", "Not too much", "Not at all", "Refused"], "question_text": "Thinking about your own household's financial situation, how much, if at all, does how the stock market is doing affect your household's financial situation?", "Asian": {"A fair amount": 74.0, "A great deal": 38.0, "Not at all": 26.0, "Not too much": 69.0}, "Black": {"A fair amount": 168.0, "A great deal": 118.0, "Not at all": 166.0, "Not too much": 243.0, "Refused": 9.0}, "Hispanic": {"A fair amount": 98.0, "A great deal": 56.0, "Not at all": 65.0, "Not too much": 141.0, "Refused": 7.0}, "Mixed Race": {"A fair amount": 48.0, "A great deal": 24.0, "Not at all": 45.0, "Not too much": 63.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Other": {"A fair amount": 16.0, "A great deal": 5.0, "Not at all": 8.0, "Not too much": 16.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Refused": {"A fair amount": 35.0, "A great deal": 12.0, "Not at all": 22.0, "Not too much": 28.0, "Refused": 3.0}, "White": {"A fair amount": 1657.0, "A great deal": 913.0, "Not at all": 994.0, "Not too much": 1678.0, "Refused": 31.0}}, "ECON4_h_W54": {"MC_options": ["A great deal", "A fair amount", "Not too much", "Not at all", "Refused"], "question_text": "Thinking about your own household's financial situation, how much, if at all, does wages and incomes in your area affect your household's financial situation?", "Asian": {"A fair amount": 51.0, "A great deal": 118.0, "Not at all": 13.0, "Not too much": 25.0}, "Black": {"A fair amount": 155.0, "A great deal": 436.0, "Not at all": 37.0, "Not too much": 72.0, "Refused": 4.0}, "Hispanic": {"A fair amount": 103.0, "A great deal": 212.0, "Not at all": 17.0, "Not too much": 29.0, "Refused": 6.0}, "Mixed Race": {"A fair amount": 52.0, "A great deal": 101.0, "Not at all": 8.0, "Not too much": 20.0}, "Other": {"A fair amount": 8.0, "A great deal": 26.0, "Not at all": 3.0, "Not too much": 8.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Refused": {"A fair amount": 33.0, "A great deal": 40.0, "Not at all": 8.0, "Not too much": 15.0, "Refused": 4.0}, "White": {"A fair amount": 1637.0, "A great deal": 2462.0, "Not at all": 371.0, "Not too much": 777.0, "Refused": 26.0}}, "ECON4_i_W54": {"MC_options": ["A great deal", "A fair amount", "Not too much", "Not at all", "Refused"], "question_text": "Thinking about your own household's financial situation, how much, if at all, does the country's tax system affect your household's financial situation?", "Asian": {"A fair amount": 81.0, "A great deal": 85.0, "Not at all": 5.0, "Not too much": 35.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Black": {"A fair amount": 225.0, "A great deal": 299.0, "Not at all": 47.0, "Not too much": 129.0, "Refused": 4.0}, "Hispanic": {"A fair amount": 135.0, "A great deal": 144.0, "Not at all": 21.0, "Not too much": 61.0, "Refused": 6.0}, "Mixed Race": {"A fair amount": 75.0, "A great deal": 65.0, "Not at all": 7.0, "Not too much": 34.0}, "Other": {"A fair amount": 15.0, "A great deal": 18.0, "Not at all": 4.0, "Not too much": 8.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Refused": {"A fair amount": 40.0, "A great deal": 34.0, "Not at all": 4.0, "Not too much": 18.0, "Refused": 4.0}, "White": {"A fair amount": 2268.0, "A great deal": 1684.0, "Not at all": 208.0, "Not too much": 1089.0, "Refused": 24.0}}, "INEQ1_W54": {"MC_options": ["Too much economic inequality", "Too little economic inequality", "About the right amount of economic inequality", "Refused"], "question_text": "Thinking about the level of economic inequality in the country these days, would you say there is", "Asian": {"About the right amount of economic inequality": 38.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Too little economic inequality": 14.0, "Too much economic inequality": 154.0}, "Black": {"About the right amount of economic inequality": 81.0, "Refused": 6.0, "Too little economic inequality": 163.0, "Too much economic inequality": 454.0}, "Hispanic": {"About the right amount of economic inequality": 60.0, "Refused": 5.0, "Too little economic inequality": 53.0, "Too much economic inequality": 249.0}, "Mixed Race": {"About the right amount of economic inequality": 38.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Too little economic inequality": 22.0, "Too much economic inequality": 119.0}, "Other": {"About the right amount of economic inequality": 12.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Too little economic inequality": 5.0, "Too much economic inequality": 27.0}, "Refused": {"About the right amount of economic inequality": 22.0, "Refused": 9.0, "Too little economic inequality": 15.0, "Too much economic inequality": 54.0}, "White": {"About the right amount of economic inequality": 1353.0, "Refused": 143.0, "Too little economic inequality": 443.0, "Too much economic inequality": 3334.0}}, "INEQ6_W54": {"MC_options": ["A great deal", "A fair amount", "Not too much", "Not at all", "Refused"], "question_text": "Thinking about children growing up in this country these days, how much, if at all, do you think their family's financial situation impacts their ability to succeed in life?", "Asian": {"A fair amount": 74.0, "A great deal": 122.0, "Not too much": 11.0}, "Black": {"A fair amount": 224.0, "A great deal": 432.0, "Not at all": 4.0, "Not too much": 43.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Hispanic": {"A fair amount": 121.0, "A great deal": 206.0, "Not at all": 4.0, "Not too much": 33.0, "Refused": 3.0}, "Mixed Race": {"A fair amount": 66.0, "A great deal": 97.0, "Not at all": 3.0, "Not too much": 15.0}, "Other": {"A fair amount": 21.0, "A great deal": 19.0, "Not at all": 1.0, "Not too much": 5.0}, "Refused": {"A fair amount": 45.0, "A great deal": 40.0, "Not at all": 2.0, "Not too much": 12.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "White": {"A fair amount": 2061.0, "A great deal": 2604.0, "Not at all": 65.0, "Not too much": 537.0, "Refused": 6.0}}, "INEQ7_W54": {"MC_options": ["A great deal", "A fair amount", "Not too much", "Not at all", "Refused"], "question_text": "Thinking about children growing up in the area where you live these days, how much, if at all, do you think their family's financial situation impacts their ability to succeed in life?", "Asian": {"A fair amount": 84.0, "A great deal": 95.0, "Not at all": 4.0, "Not too much": 24.0}, "Black": {"A fair amount": 247.0, "A great deal": 392.0, "Not at all": 9.0, "Not too much": 55.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Hispanic": {"A fair amount": 138.0, "A great deal": 184.0, "Not at all": 5.0, "Not too much": 38.0, "Refused": 2.0}, "Mixed Race": {"A fair amount": 78.0, "A great deal": 77.0, "Not at all": 4.0, "Not too much": 22.0}, "Other": {"A fair amount": 16.0, "A great deal": 22.0, "Not at all": 1.0, "Not too much": 7.0}, "Refused": {"A fair amount": 38.0, "A great deal": 36.0, "Not at all": 4.0, "Not too much": 20.0, "Refused": 2.0}, "White": {"A fair amount": 2153.0, "A great deal": 2228.0, "Not at all": 104.0, "Not too much": 763.0, "Refused": 25.0}}, "INEQ9_W54": {"MC_options": ["Give direct assistance to people who are poor in the form of cash payments or tax credits", "Invest in education and job training programs for people who are poor", "Refused"], "question_text": "In order to address economic inequality in this country, do you think it would be better for the government to", "Asian": {"Give direct assistance to people who are poor in the form of cash payments or tax credits": 25.0, "Invest in education and job training programs for people who are poor": 180.0, "Refused": 2.0}, "Black": {"Give direct assistance to people who are poor in the form of cash payments or tax credits": 145.0, "Invest in education and job training programs for people who are poor": 550.0, "Refused": 9.0}, "Hispanic": {"Give direct assistance to people who are poor in the form of cash payments or tax credits": 55.0, "Invest in education and job training programs for people who are poor": 307.0, "Refused": 5.0}, "Mixed Race": {"Give direct assistance to people who are poor in the form of cash payments or tax credits": 33.0, "Invest in education and job training programs for people who are poor": 145.0, "Refused": 3.0}, "Other": {"Give direct assistance to people who are poor in the form of cash payments or tax credits": 5.0, "Invest in education and job training programs for people who are poor": 40.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Refused": {"Give direct assistance to people who are poor in the form of cash payments or tax credits": 7.0, "Invest in education and job training programs for people who are poor": 88.0, "Refused": 5.0}, "White": {"Give direct assistance to people who are poor in the form of cash payments or tax credits": 626.0, "Invest in education and job training programs for people who are poor": 4526.0, "Refused": 121.0}}, "ECON5_a_W54": {"MC_options": ["Helping a lot", "Helping a little", "Hurting a little", "Hurting a lot", "Neither helping nor hurting", "Refused"], "question_text": "Do you think the country's current economic conditions are helping or hurting you and your family?", "Asian": {"Helping a little": 45.0, "Helping a lot": 21.0, "Hurting a little": 56.0, "Hurting a lot": 24.0, "Neither helping nor hurting": 60.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Black": {"Helping a little": 100.0, "Helping a lot": 35.0, "Hurting a little": 245.0, "Hurting a lot": 201.0, "Neither helping nor hurting": 117.0, "Refused": 6.0}, "Hispanic": {"Helping a little": 77.0, "Helping a lot": 27.0, "Hurting a little": 125.0, "Hurting a lot": 80.0, "Neither helping nor hurting": 55.0, "Refused": 3.0}, "Mixed Race": {"Helping a little": 37.0, "Helping a lot": 8.0, "Hurting a little": 67.0, "Hurting a lot": 34.0, "Neither helping nor hurting": 34.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Other": {"Helping a little": 10.0, "Helping a lot": 3.0, "Hurting a little": 13.0, "Hurting a lot": 12.0, "Neither helping nor hurting": 7.0, "Refused": 1.0}, "Refused": {"Helping a little": 14.0, "Helping a lot": 10.0, "Hurting a little": 19.0, "Hurting a lot": 18.0, "Neither helping nor hurting": 34.0, "Refused": 5.0}, "White": {"Helping a little": 1354.0, "Helping a lot": 523.0, "Hurting a little": 1562.0, "Hurting a lot": 580.0, "Neither helping nor hurting": 1215.0, "Refused": 39.0}}, "ECIMPa_W54": {"MC_options": ["Too much power and influence", "Not enough power and influence", "About the right amount", "Refused"], "question_text": "How much power and influence do you think politicians have on today's economy?", "Asian": {"About the right amount": 22.0, "Not enough power and influence": 12.0, "Too much power and influence": 173.0}, "Black": {"About the right amount": 69.0, "Not enough power and influence": 59.0, "Refused": 6.0, "Too much power and influence": 570.0}, "Hispanic": {"About the right amount": 39.0, "Not enough power and influence": 18.0, "Refused": 7.0, "Too much power and influence": 303.0}, "Mixed Race": {"About the right amount": 21.0, "Not enough power and influence": 10.0, "Too much power and influence": 150.0}, "Other": {"About the right amount": 7.0, "Not enough power and influence": 1.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Too much power and influence": 37.0}, "Refused": {"About the right amount": 13.0, "Not enough power and influence": 4.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Too much power and influence": 82.0}, "White": {"About the right amount": 568.0, "Not enough power and influence": 209.0, "Refused": 49.0, "Too much power and influence": 4447.0}}, "WORRY2a_W54": {"MC_options": ["Every day", "Almost every day", "Sometimes", "Rarely", "Never", "Refused"], "question_text": "How often, if ever, do you worry about the amount of debt you have?", "Asian": {"Almost every day": 20.0, "Every day": 37.0, "Never": 47.0, "Rarely": 51.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Sometimes": 51.0}, "Black": {"Almost every day": 131.0, "Every day": 257.0, "Never": 58.0, "Rarely": 67.0, "Refused": 8.0, "Sometimes": 183.0}, "Hispanic": {"Almost every day": 67.0, "Every day": 107.0, "Never": 37.0, "Rarely": 47.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Sometimes": 106.0}, "Mixed Race": {"Almost every day": 34.0, "Every day": 59.0, "Never": 20.0, "Rarely": 24.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Sometimes": 43.0}, "Other": {"Almost every day": 7.0, "Every day": 7.0, "Never": 6.0, "Rarely": 9.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Sometimes": 15.0}, "Refused": {"Almost every day": 14.0, "Every day": 19.0, "Never": 26.0, "Rarely": 17.0, "Refused": 4.0, "Sometimes": 20.0}, "White": {"Almost every day": 771.0, "Every day": 996.0, "Never": 1070.0, "Rarely": 1003.0, "Refused": 30.0, "Sometimes": 1403.0}}, "WORRY2c_W54": {"MC_options": ["Every day", "Almost every day", "Sometimes", "Rarely", "Never", "Refused"], "question_text": "How often, if ever, do you worry about paying your bills?", "Asian": {"Almost every day": 23.0, "Every day": 36.0, "Never": 29.0, "Rarely": 59.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Sometimes": 59.0}, "Black": {"Almost every day": 124.0, "Every day": 253.0, "Never": 41.0, "Rarely": 95.0, "Refused": 7.0, "Sometimes": 184.0}, "Hispanic": {"Almost every day": 71.0, "Every day": 104.0, "Never": 26.0, "Rarely": 59.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Sometimes": 105.0}, "Mixed Race": {"Almost every day": 29.0, "Every day": 49.0, "Never": 17.0, "Rarely": 29.0, "Sometimes": 57.0}, "Other": {"Almost every day": 7.0, "Every day": 11.0, "Never": 1.0, "Rarely": 10.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Sometimes": 15.0}, "Refused": {"Almost every day": 13.0, "Every day": 23.0, "Never": 20.0, "Rarely": 18.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Sometimes": 24.0}, "White": {"Almost every day": 721.0, "Every day": 913.0, "Never": 867.0, "Rarely": 1230.0, "Refused": 22.0, "Sometimes": 1520.0}}, "WORRY2d_W54": {"MC_options": ["Every day", "Almost every day", "Sometimes", "Rarely", "Never", "Refused"], "question_text": "How often, if ever, do you worry about the cost of health care for you and your family?", "Asian": {"Almost every day": 26.0, "Every day": 31.0, "Never": 17.0, "Rarely": 35.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Sometimes": 95.0}, "Black": {"Almost every day": 112.0, "Every day": 198.0, "Never": 61.0, "Rarely": 107.0, "Refused": 7.0, "Sometimes": 219.0}, "Hispanic": {"Almost every day": 63.0, "Every day": 105.0, "Never": 31.0, "Rarely": 54.0, "Refused": 4.0, "Sometimes": 110.0}, "Mixed Race": {"Almost every day": 45.0, "Every day": 41.0, "Never": 13.0, "Rarely": 24.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Sometimes": 57.0}, "Other": {"Almost every day": 6.0, "Every day": 10.0, "Never": 2.0, "Rarely": 3.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Sometimes": 23.0}, "Refused": {"Almost every day": 14.0, "Every day": 19.0, "Never": 14.0, "Rarely": 19.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Sometimes": 32.0}, "White": {"Almost every day": 852.0, "Every day": 900.0, "Never": 498.0, "Rarely": 951.0, "Refused": 24.0, "Sometimes": 2048.0}}, "WORRY2e_W54": {"MC_options": ["Every day", "Almost every day", "Sometimes", "Rarely", "Never", "Refused"], "question_text": "How often, if ever, do you worry about being able to save enough for your retirement?", "Asian": {"Almost every day": 35.0, "Every day": 36.0, "Never": 21.0, "Rarely": 31.0, "Refused": 4.0, "Sometimes": 80.0}, "Black": {"Almost every day": 119.0, "Every day": 247.0, "Never": 57.0, "Rarely": 78.0, "Refused": 11.0, "Sometimes": 192.0}, "Hispanic": {"Almost every day": 78.0, "Every day": 119.0, "Never": 17.0, "Rarely": 41.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Sometimes": 109.0}, "Mixed Race": {"Almost every day": 45.0, "Every day": 50.0, "Never": 11.0, "Rarely": 15.0, "Sometimes": 60.0}, "Other": {"Almost every day": 12.0, "Every day": 10.0, "Never": 3.0, "Rarely": 3.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Sometimes": 16.0}, "Refused": {"Almost every day": 15.0, "Every day": 26.0, "Never": 12.0, "Rarely": 18.0, "Refused": 4.0, "Sometimes": 25.0}, "White": {"Almost every day": 951.0, "Every day": 1118.0, "Never": 617.0, "Rarely": 716.0, "Refused": 88.0, "Sometimes": 1783.0}}, "FINANCEa_W54": {"MC_options": ["Yes", "have this", "No", "do not have this", "Refused"], "question_text": "Do you have a savings account?", "Asian": {"No, do not have this": 37.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have this": 167.0}, "Black": {"No, do not have this": 228.0, "Refused": 20.0, "Yes, have this": 456.0}, "Hispanic": {"No, do not have this": 114.0, "Refused": 4.0, "Yes, have this": 249.0}, "Mixed Race": {"No, do not have this": 43.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Yes, have this": 136.0}, "Other": {"No, do not have this": 16.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have this": 27.0}, "Refused": {"No, do not have this": 25.0, "Refused": 8.0, "Yes, have this": 67.0}, "White": {"No, do not have this": 1149.0, "Refused": 69.0, "Yes, have this": 4055.0}}, "FINANCEb_W54": {"MC_options": ["Yes", "have this", "No", "do not have this", "Refused"], "question_text": "Do you have an IRA, 401K or a similar kind of retirement account?", "Asian": {"No, do not have this": 60.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have this": 144.0}, "Black": {"No, do not have this": 356.0, "Refused": 19.0, "Yes, have this": 329.0}, "Hispanic": {"No, do not have this": 173.0, "Refused": 4.0, "Yes, have this": 190.0}, "Mixed Race": {"No, do not have this": 79.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have this": 99.0}, "Other": {"No, do not have this": 17.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have this": 26.0}, "Refused": {"No, do not have this": 39.0, "Refused": 8.0, "Yes, have this": 53.0}, "White": {"No, do not have this": 1568.0, "Refused": 80.0, "Yes, have this": 3625.0}}, "FINANCEc_W54": {"MC_options": ["Yes", "have this", "No", "do not have this", "Refused"], "question_text": "Do you have personal investments in stocks, bonds or mutual funds other than those held in an IRA or 401K?", "Asian": {"No, do not have this": 98.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have this": 106.0}, "Black": {"No, do not have this": 501.0, "Refused": 21.0, "Yes, have this": 182.0}, "Hispanic": {"No, do not have this": 250.0, "Refused": 7.0, "Yes, have this": 110.0}, "Mixed Race": {"No, do not have this": 118.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Yes, have this": 61.0}, "Other": {"No, do not have this": 31.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have this": 12.0}, "Refused": {"No, do not have this": 52.0, "Refused": 7.0, "Yes, have this": 41.0}, "White": {"No, do not have this": 2786.0, "Refused": 76.0, "Yes, have this": 2411.0}}, "DEBTa_W54": {"MC_options": ["Yes", "have this", "No", "do not have this", "Refused"], "question_text": "Do you have the following type of loans or debt: Credit card debt", "Asian": {"No, do not have this": 110.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Yes, have this": 96.0}, "Black": {"No, do not have this": 249.0, "Refused": 16.0, "Yes, have this": 439.0}, "Hispanic": {"No, do not have this": 139.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Yes, have this": 226.0}, "Mixed Race": {"No, do not have this": 70.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Yes, have this": 110.0}, "Other": {"No, do not have this": 20.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have this": 23.0}, "Refused": {"No, do not have this": 45.0, "Refused": 4.0, "Yes, have this": 51.0}, "White": {"No, do not have this": 2571.0, "Refused": 48.0, "Yes, have this": 2654.0}}, "DEBTb_W54": {"MC_options": ["Yes", "have this", "No", "do not have this", "Refused"], "question_text": "Do you have the following type of loans or debt: Car loan", "Asian": {"No, do not have this": 137.0, "Yes, have this": 70.0}, "Black": {"No, do not have this": 386.0, "Refused": 12.0, "Yes, have this": 306.0}, "Hispanic": {"No, do not have this": 212.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have this": 152.0}, "Mixed Race": {"No, do not have this": 106.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Yes, have this": 74.0}, "Other": {"No, do not have this": 28.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have this": 15.0}, "Refused": {"No, do not have this": 60.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have this": 37.0}, "White": {"No, do not have this": 3053.0, "Refused": 59.0, "Yes, have this": 2161.0}}, "DEBTc_W54": {"MC_options": ["Yes", "have this", "No", "do not have this", "Refused"], "question_text": "Do you have the following type of loans or debt: Student loans", "Asian": {"No, do not have this": 157.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Yes, have this": 49.0}, "Black": {"No, do not have this": 409.0, "Refused": 11.0, "Yes, have this": 284.0}, "Hispanic": {"No, do not have this": 250.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have this": 114.0}, "Mixed Race": {"No, do not have this": 125.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Yes, have this": 55.0}, "Other": {"No, do not have this": 36.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have this": 7.0}, "Refused": {"No, do not have this": 76.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have this": 21.0}, "White": {"No, do not have this": 4123.0, "Refused": 48.0, "Yes, have this": 1102.0}}, "DEBTd_W54": {"MC_options": ["Yes", "have this", "No", "do not have this", "Refused"], "question_text": "Do you have the following type of loans or debt: A mortgage or a home loan", "Asian": {"No, do not have this": 118.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Yes, have this": 88.0}, "Black": {"No, do not have this": 457.0, "Refused": 13.0, "Yes, have this": 234.0}, "Hispanic": {"No, do not have this": 237.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have this": 127.0}, "Mixed Race": {"No, do not have this": 95.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Yes, have this": 85.0}, "Other": {"No, do not have this": 25.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have this": 18.0}, "Refused": {"No, do not have this": 56.0, "Refused": 4.0, "Yes, have this": 40.0}, "White": {"No, do not have this": 2616.0, "Refused": 52.0, "Yes, have this": 2605.0}}, "DEBTe_W54": {"MC_options": ["Yes", "have this", "No", "do not have this", "Refused"], "question_text": "Do you have the following type of loans or debt: Debt from medical bills", "Asian": {"No, do not have this": 177.0, "Refused": 1.0, "Yes, have this": 29.0}, "Black": {"No, do not have this": 401.0, "Refused": 11.0, "Yes, have this": 292.0}, "Hispanic": {"No, do not have this": 256.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have this": 108.0}, "Mixed Race": {"No, do not have this": 121.0, "Yes, have this": 60.0}, "Other": {"No, do not have this": 32.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have this": 11.0}, "Refused": {"No, do not have this": 72.0, "Refused": 4.0, "Yes, have this": 24.0}, "White": {"No, do not have this": 3992.0, "Refused": 46.0, "Yes, have this": 1235.0}}, "BENEFITSa_W54": {"MC_options": ["Yes", "have received in the past 12 months", "No", "have not received in the past 12 months", "Refused"], "question_text": "Have you or anyone in your household received food assistance, such as SNAP benefits government services and benefits in the past 12 months?", "Asian": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 191.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 14.0}, "Black": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 500.0, "Refused": 15.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 189.0}, "Hispanic": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 309.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 56.0}, "Mixed Race": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 147.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 34.0}, "Other": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 33.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 10.0}, "Refused": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 88.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 9.0}, "White": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 4800.0, "Refused": 32.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 441.0}}, "BENEFITSb_W54": {"MC_options": ["Yes", "have received in the past 12 months", "No", "have not received in the past 12 months", "Refused"], "question_text": "Have you or anyone in your household received medicaid benefits government services and benefits in the past 12 months?", "Asian": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 170.0, "Refused": 4.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 33.0}, "Black": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 459.0, "Refused": 12.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 233.0}, "Hispanic": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 277.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 87.0}, "Mixed Race": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 146.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 35.0}, "Other": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 32.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 11.0}, "Refused": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 77.0, "Refused": 4.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 19.0}, "White": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 4402.0, "Refused": 43.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 828.0}}, "BENEFITSc_W54": {"MC_options": ["Yes", "have received in the past 12 months", "No", "have not received in the past 12 months", "Refused"], "question_text": "Have you or anyone in your household received unemployment benefits government services and benefits in the past 12 months?", "Asian": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 192.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 12.0}, "Black": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 650.0, "Refused": 12.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 42.0}, "Hispanic": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 344.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 21.0}, "Mixed Race": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 173.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 8.0}, "Other": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 41.0, "Refused": 2.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 3.0}, "Refused": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 95.0, "Refused": 3.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 2.0}, "White": {"No, have not received in the past 12 months": 5044.0, "Refused": 38.0, "Yes, have received in the past 12 months": 191.0}}}